Research Interests

My research focuses on language model reasoning. I particularly insterested in (1) reducing hallucination and enhancing factuality with retrieval augmented generation (RAG), and long-context understanding; (2) empowering the reasoning ability of LLMs with multiple data resources for various practical scenarios, including tabular data for table-based reasoning, programming language for code generation/understanding, web pages for web mining, etc.

Education

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, CA, USA

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

October 2020 - Now

· Advised by Prof. Jingbo Shang

Peking University

Beijing, CHN

B.S. in Computer Science

September 2016 - July 2020

• Outstanding Graduate of Beijing City and Peking University (Top 5%)

Work Experience

Google Cloud AI Research

Sunnyvale, CA

Student Researcher April 2023 - Now

- Work with Dr. Chen-Yu Lee, Dr. Chun-Liang Li.
- · Propose CHAIN-OF-TABLE to improve tabular reasoning ability of large language models. The paper is accepted by ICLR '24.
- The algorithm has been integrated into the products in Google Cloud.
- Chain-of-Table enables step-by-step reasoning with table inputs by simplifying complex tables into more informative and manageable segments. LLMs can now reason about tables more effectively similar to the thought process of a human analyst.

Google Research Mountain View, CA

Student Researcher

June 2022 - September 2022

- Work with Dr. Sandeep Tata, Dr. Yichao Zhou, Dr. Wei Wei, Dr. Chen-Yu Lee.
- Propose a new public benchmark for visually-rich document understanding focusing on the few-shot setting and template structure learning. The paper is accepted by KDD '23.
- Propose A type-aware evaluation toolkit to evaluate the performance of language models in visually-rich document understanding.

Adobe Research Remote

Research Intern

June 2021 - September 2021

- Work with Dr. Vlad Morariu, Dr. Tong Sun.
- Propose a layout-aware pre-trained language model for visually-rich document understanding using multi-granular inputs to encode template structure. The paper is accepted by EMNLP '22.

Microsoft Research Asia Beijing, CHN

Research Intern

September 2020 - March 2021

- · Work with Dr. Lei Cui.
- Propose an auto-regressive language model to encode multi-modal features and extract reading order in visually-rich documents. The paper is accepted by EMNLP '21.
- · Propose an automatic approach to build large reading order dataset from XML metadata of Microsoft Office files.

Papers & Pre-prints

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=S_wQccsAAAAJ

- Chain-of-Table: Evolving Tables in the Reasoning Chain for Table Understanding
 Zilong Wang, Hao Zhang, Chun-Liang Li, Julian Martin Eisenschlos, Vincent Perot, Zifeng Wang, Lesly Miculicich, Yasuhisa Fujii, Jingbo Shang,
 Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister
 - The International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024
- LDB: A Large Language Model Debugger via Verifying Runtime Execution Step-by-step Li Zhong, Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang arXiv preprint arXiv:2402.16906 (Preprint), 2023
- 3. Can ChatGPT replace StackOverflow? A Study on Robustness and Reliability of Large Language Model Code Generation Li Zhong, **Zilong Wang**

The 38th Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023

May 27, 2024

- 4. LMDX: Language Model-based Document Information Extraction and Localization Vincent Perot, Kai Kang, Florian Luisier, Guolong Su, Xiaoyu Sun, Ramya Sree Boppana, Zilong Wang, Jiaqi Mu, Hao Zhang, Nan Hua arXiv preprint arXiv:2309.10952 (Preprint), 2023
- Towards Zero-shot Relation Extraction in Web Mining: A Multimodal Approach with Relative XML Path Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023 (EMNLP), 2023

- 6. VRDU: A Benchmark for Visually-rich Document Understanding Zilong Wang, Yichao Zhou, Wei Wei, Chen-Yu Lee, Sandeep Tata Proc. of the 29th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2023
- 7. MGDoc: Pre-training with Multi-granular Hierarchy for Document Image Understanding **Zilong Wang**, Jiuxiang Gu, Chris Tensmeyer, Nikolaos Barmpalios, Ani Nenkova, Tong Sun, Jingbo Shang and Vlad I. Morariu Proc. of the 2022 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2022
- 8. Formulating Few-shot Fine-tuning Towards Language Model Pre-training: A Pilot Study on Named Entity Recognition Zihan Wang, Kewen Zhao, **Zilong Wang**, Jingbo Shang Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2022 (EMNLP), 2022
- 9. Towards Few-shot Entity Recognition in Document Images: A Label-aware Sequence-to-Sequence Framework Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2022 (ACL), 2022
- 10. LayoutReader: Pre-training of Text and Layout for Reading Order Detection

Zilong Wang, Yiheng Xu, Lei Cui, Jingbo Shang, Furu Wei Proc. of the 2021 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2021

11. DocStruct: A Multimodal Method to Extract Hierarchy Structure in Document for General Form Understanding Zilong Wang, Mingjie Zhan, Xuebo Liu and Ding Liang Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2020 (EMNLP), 2020

12. Exploring Semantic Capacity of Terms Jie Huang*, **Zilong Wang***, Kevin Chang, Wen-mei Hwu and JinJun Xiong Proc. of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020

Honors & Awards

2020-2021 UCSD Powell Fellowship 2020-2021 UCSD Jacob School of Engineering Fellowship 2020 Summa Cum Laude of Beijing City 2020

Summa Cum Laude of Peking University

Professional Service

ICLR (2024), NeurIPS (2022, 2023), ACL (2022, 2023) EMNLP (2022, 2023), ICML (2024), COLM (2024), CVPR (2024), CtrlGen Reviewer Workshop(2021), COLING (2022)

Skills

Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Language Modeling, Multimodal Data Mining, Visually-rich Document **Skills** Understanding, Webpage Information Mining

Programming Python (PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras), Java, C++, C#, Javascript

MAY 27, 2024